<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the environment on The Byte</title>
    <link>https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/tags/the-environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the environment on The Byte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/tags/the-environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is causing Climate Change? Is it us or is it just a natural event?</title>
      <link>https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/posts/what-is-causing-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/posts/what-is-causing-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>Climate Change is a huge global issue that we are currently experiencing on the planet. It’s been a huge problem known for decades but only now are we actually seeing the effects of it on the news. From devastating wildfires to powerful surges of floods. We are living dangerously close to the point of no return, so close to the start of mass extinctions. So how can we solve this? Well, we first need to understand what is causing Climate Change before we try to find more solutions to stop this global disaster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Power: Are we playing with fire?</title>
      <link>https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/posts/nuclear-power-are-we-playing-with-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thebytenewspaper.github.io/posts/nuclear-power-are-we-playing-with-fire/</guid>
      <description>Nuclear Power is a clean and remarkably efficient way of boiling water (the steam formed turn turbines) to produce electricity. Currently, this scaled-up, over-complicated kettle powers 20% of the United Kingdom. One Kilogram of Uranium can generate the same amount of power that it would take 126 gallons of oil, 1 ton of coal or 17,000 cubic feet of natural gas to generate. Unlike fossil fuels, nuclear fuel does not release large quantities of harmful emissions into our atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
